so hi my name is Joe brewer and I'm a
change strategist so I help people
design changes in culture and one of the
things that I want to share is a very
old very simple practice that is
extremely valuable for creating
large-scale change and that can be a
large-scale change in your own life like
for restructuring how you live to become
more healthy and more happy or bored
scale change as in impacting large
numbers of people and changing the
emphasis and priorities of an entire
community in both cases there's a very
simple a very profound thing that you
can do and that is to recognize that
large changes happen by taking a
sequence of small simple steps so if you
are to start out with a simple task that
you understand to build toward a big
goal then you just perform that task
well and then move on to the next task
and as an example of how this works in a
very practical way something that I've
been doing for years is practicing a
particular kind of stretching fitness
training that I've learned from many
years of studying dance and martial arts
when I was younger and what I do is I
put together a sequence of stretching
and moving exercises that take between
60 and 90 minutes if I do all of them
and what I find myself doing from time
to time is elapsing from doing this
activity and my body becomes more stiff
and more strained and I'm more prone to
injury and more likely to become sick so
what I do is I reintroduce the practice
of daily stretching now daily stretching
is something that is best done with a
very simple routine to follow where you
know what your first movement is and it
naturally leads to the second movement
which leads to the third movement so my
stretch routine starts with the rolling
of my neck
followed by
putting my head side to side and then
doing some movements with my shoulders
and my arms kind of working from the top
of my body downward and then doing some
no ankle foot movements knee and hip
movements to loosen up the joints
throughout my body
before starting deep stretches I know
what's amazing about this stretch
routine is not what it does in any given
day so if I do this routine for an hour
today makes a little difference I
definitely feel better I have more
energy but what really is amazing is if
I do this stretch routine every day over
and over again about three years ago I
did this where I did my 60-minute
stretch routine every day for seven
straight months where I only missed the
routine on something like three or four
of those days so for more than a half a
year I did an hour of stretching every
day and what I noticed was that I
gradually built up a very different body
that I had when I started so I would
notice myself reaching new plateaus of
physical ability and fitness every few
weeks and I noticed that I had a much
deeper awareness and sensitivity to my
body that gradually developed over time
so by doing the stretch routine of a
sequence of simple positions and moves
every day day after day week after week
month after month I built up a very
different kind of body and a very
different kind of lifestyle for health
and fitness so in the same way we were
to think about what it's like to go to
college and to get a degree where you
master a field of study so I did this
for physics once upon a time I didn't
learn all the physics in one day I
didn't sit down and download it with a
microchip the way that neo did in the
Matrix movies I was able to go through a
curriculum for years of Education where
every day at least during the times in
schools in session I would go to a class
sit for an hour with a professor and
they would go through one or two topics
and we would then go and do a set of
exercises some problem sets over the
next few days and we'd bring them back
to class and over the period of several
years I learned a different way of
thinking which was the mathematical
analysis and the scientific method of
physics so the thing that I'm wanting to
convey here is that this way of
methodically approaching a long process
of change as a way of achieving larger
goals is something that is tried and
true throughout history it's a you could
call it a best practice a wisdom
tradition something that is a tried and
true in many different cultural settings
and something that I can validate from
my own life experience so as you set
your own New Year's resolutions as many
of you may be prone to do at this time
of year think about how you're illogical
whatever it may be is something that is
achievable but only if you consistently
methodological or methodically patiently
build up a change over time so I'm doing
this in my own work so for those of you
followed my work and seeing the things
that I've been able to accomplish over
the span of several years you'd see that
some very large high-profile impacts
some positive outcomes came about that
many people would say oh how is that
even possible how did you do that well
my answer is that I trust this process
so when I left my ph.d program ten years
ago to set out on a different path to
study the cognitive and behavioral
sciences and try to apply it to global
sustainability issues then I moved
through a process of learning about
political behavior and working in
politics and you can see every step of
the way if you were to zoom in and watch
what I was doing on a daily basis you
would see that I was practicing this
skill and that's how I've been able to
build up to the place that I am today
and I now routinely set large goals for
myself
they take months or years to accomplish
and then I practice the patients and the
introspection and the daily rituals that
I need which I usually don't know what
those rituals are when I start so I also
have a process of figuring out what
those are to build up to the place where
I can achieve big things and this is
something that I'd like for a lot of
other people to learn how to do and
that's why I'm recording this in this
video for you today so I hope you find
it useful I definitely find it very
powerful in my own life and of course
feel free to drop any questions or
comments and the comment thread below
this video and I'll do my best to answer
them so there you go I hope this is
helpful for you I started making big
changes in small steps and see what you
can accomplish